

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

W: linkedin.com/in/zunaib-imtiaz/

W: zunaib.com

E: zunaib60@gmail.com **P**: +92 308 4225537

L: Johar Town, Lahore, Pakistan

PERSONAL INFO

Software Engineer with two plus years of organizational and one plus years of freelance Full Stack Development experience developing projects from diverse domains. Got experience in developing fast and responsive user interfaces with modular application servers. My strongest suit is pixel perfect user interface development. Love learning new things and tools every day. Driven individual with the ability to adapt to any situation and potential to grow self and others.



WORK EXPERIENCE

FRONTEND DEVELOPER - EMPERIA

AUG 2021 – PRESENT

At **Emperia**, started working as a sole Frontend Developer. Built GrapesJS project from ground up to kickstart a new venture at Emperia. Working on developing user interface part of the application while doing R & D on Grapes JS. Performed the following duties,

- Integrated GrapesJS into a basic ReactJS Typescript project to create a prebuilt User Interface Template resulting in easier user interface creation.
- Developed a drag and drop User Interface Components / Templates Project from scratch using ReactJS, Typescript, GrapesJS, Antd, HTML, Vanilla JS and CSS that can be used to export full-fledged User Interfaces created from templates as HTML / JS / CSS Code and it helped to speed up the user interface development part of the whole application.
- Added Custom Panels and Traits to Grapes JS that yielded in attaching any kind of html properties and action handlers on the fly.
- Integrated AntD to GrapesJS to edit the look of GrapesJS Editor and add custom Modals that can fetch configurations from Amazon API specific to the selected client.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - AFINITI

MAY 2019 - PRESENT

At Afiniti, started as an Analyst Software Engineer, initially worked on the user interface development part of an application with excellence for 10 months got me promoted to Software Engineer and started working on full stack applications, building the whole application from scratch to deployments, developing services and coaching junior employees. Worked on projects from diversified domains performing following duties,

- Coached junior team members on building excellent pixel perfect user interfaces using best coding practices, problem solving approaches, code management and code versioning.
- Built codebases from ground up, setting up bullet proof repositories and coding guidelines with appropriate Visual Studio Code Extensions.
- Implemented core structure of repositories i.e., layout of the application to give my team members a pacy start and easy to work codebase.
- Reviewed codebases / pull requests and maintaining coding standards with mutual agreement and learning.
- Developed fast, reliable, responsive and flexible user interfaces using ReactJS, NextJS with ES6 to get a fluid visual appearance that engaged a lot more users and improved user experience.
- Developed user interfaces for multiple devices considering specific layout, cross

- browser compatibility, useability using SCSS grids / breakpoints and ReactJS Hooks to attain multi device support that catered a more diverse range of users.
- Integrated global state managing technologies like Redux to direct the global usage of information all across the application that made global data management easier to handle.
- Developed a custom ReactJS component library for Afiniti using ReactJS, SCSS, Storybook and deployed it to Afiniti's NPM Proxy for the whole organization to build user interfaces.
- Acquired hands on experience with 3rd party UI Libraries integration like AntDesign, Chakra UI, Material UI and more UI Libraries to get a much pacy development pace.
- Developed Complex Dynamic Forms using UseForm and Formik like 3rd party npm packages so that a lot of data can be handled and validated in an organized way.
- Developed scalable and modular Application Servers using NodeJS, Python Flask and Hasura so that it can be attached to any frontend library or framework with ease
- Developed high end performance APIs using Redis to cater load balancing of increasing requests per second that resulted in faster response times.
- Developed API Middleware Services using NodeJS to cater a higher order functionality for every API call.
- Deployed Full Stack Applications using Nginx, Docker and GitHub to make the application go live and be interactable.
- Worked on Integrating new features into Legacy Projects so that legacy projects are also being maintained.
- Worked on Production Bugs and Issues to keep up the client satisfaction and a bug free application.

FREELANCE WEBDEVELOPER - UPWORK

JAN 2020 – JUNE 2021

Working on **Upwork**, dealt with projects from diverse domains and technologies. Encountered issues and obstacles out of an organizational environment on Upwork which led me to grow personally and professionally improving customer experience and my technical skills. While being a Freelancer, following duties were performed,

- Developed Client websites using ReactJS, NodeJS, SCSS, MongoDB with custom client-oriented functionalities to achieve excellent performance and best possible visual appearance with good code practices.
- Converted PSD Designs into ReactJS Pages with pixel perfect designs and accurate color schemes to reflect a visual idea into a visual product.
- Worked on Shopify to develop websites, integrated Vanilla JavaScript and SCSS into Shopify for custom features so that some not out of the box functionalities could be achieved.
- Deployed Websites to custom domains using GitHub Pages, Nginx and Docker to make them interactable.
- Attained 100 percent Client satisfaction with my fast response and revisions.



EDUCATION

BACHELOR IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING COMSATS, LAHORE

BACHELORS DEGREE | SEP 2015 - JUN 2019

INTERMEDIATE IN PRE - ENGINEERING GOVT. SCIENCE COLLEGE, LAHORE INTERMEDIATE DEGREE | SEP 2013 – JUN 2015



- ReactJS
- NextJS
- JavaScript
- FS6
- TypeScript
- HTML 5/CSS 3
- SCSS / Theming

- Storybook
- NodeJS
- Python
- Hasura
- MongoDB
- MySQL
- PhpMyAdmin

- Docker
- Nginx
- Git Versioning
- Bitbucket
- JIRA
- Confluence

Additionally, worked in numerous other languages too,

- Worked on NumPy, Tensor-flow, Keras, Open-CV, Nvidia CUDA for Machine learning development.
- Worked on Back-end Technologies like GraphQL and Python Flask.
- Worked on Custom Styling with SCSS, Mix-ins, Variables and Media Queries.
- Worked on building Storybook from scratch and modifying it to my needs.
- Worked for community, answering community questions on stack overflow too.

HONOURS & AWARDS

EXCELLENT PERFORMANCE

AFINITI

Certificate for excellent performance and commendable work during first year of my services.

EXCEPTIONAL WORK

IVY ALUMNI

Certificate of appreciation presented for exceptional work in developing next generation AI Solutions at Afiniti, a venture of Columbia and IVY Alum Zia Chishti.



CFI REVIEW

www.cfireview.com | 2020

- Worked as a Front-End Lead to develop a custom designed user interface with cross browser compatibility, responsiveness and delivered the project to the client at Upwork for development of a custom Progressive Web Application using ReactJS, SCSS, AntDesign backed by NodeJS and MongoDB.
- Integrated React-Quill to develop blogging system using custom handlers.

OUR FAMILY TALES

www.ourfamilytales.com | 2021

- Worked as a Front-End Lead to setup a shopify store with client specific custom requirements and delivered the project to the client at Upwork for development of a shopify store with functionalities that are not provided out of the box using Vanilla JavaScript and SCSS.
- Integrated Vanilla JavaScript and SCSS to build custom forms that allow to dynamically update form fields.

AIROKIT

- Worked as a Project Lead to build and deploy a purely Afiniti specific component library consisting of almost 50 plus responsive, custom designed components used to develop web projects in Afiniti and delivered a fully functional component library under 6 months.
- Built the component library from ground up using ReactJS, Typescript, Storybook, SCSS, Rollup and some 3rd party npm packages.
- Integrated 3rd party Afiniti paid fonts to maintain consistency and deployed the component library to Afiniti's custom npm proxy.

• Integrated Jest to test every component in every way before deployments.

OVERSIGHT

- Worked as a Full Stack Developer to develop complex, pixel perfect user interfaces and a load balanced, caching application server. Implementing requirements provided by higher authorities and delivered the project on Afiniti's behalf to clients like AT&T, Avaya, Genesys, Cisco and much more for the development of a statistics and status monitoring system using ReactJS, Redux, SCSS, Airokit backed by NodeJS, PostgreSQL and Redis.
- Maintained the project for excellent support fixed production bugs and doing hotfixes as fast as possible.
- Developed two newer and better versions of the project using the same user interface and Java, Golang for the server side.

OVERSIGHT SIGNALS MANAGER

- Worked as a Front-End Lead to develop a user interface capable of displaying dense data effectively on a single screen and delivered the project for Afiniti in under a month for the effective management of data consumed by Oversight using ReactJS, Typescript, Apollo Client, AntDesign, SCSS, UseForm backed by Hasura, GraphQL, NodeJS and PostgreSQL.
- Integrated Yarn workspaces to handle packages and dependencies for a mono repository.
- Maintained the project actively for newer features and production issues.

THE SEEK

- Worked as a Project Lead to develop a client specific user interface, artificially intelligent application server and delivered the project to the client for development of a crime surveillance system to detect crime actions and violent objects using ReactJS, SCSS, AntDesign backed by Python, Python Flask, PyMongo, TensorFlow, Keras, OpenCV, NumPy, Nvidia CUDA.
- Gathered images to build datasets for training models.
- Preprocessed datasets to classify images and train activity recognition and objection detection models using python scripts.
- Developed python models for image classification.

VOGUE JUNCTION

- Final Year Project Bachelors in Software Engineering
- Lead the team of 3 developers to develop a hybrid application having some functionalities of YouTube, Medium, Instagram and an E-commerce Store using ReactJS, Redux, CSS backed by NodeJS, MongoDB following industry's best practices of development including proper commenting, use of proper naming conventions and merging strategies